Sahil Ajmera

https://sahil-ajmera.github.io | sa7810@rit.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-ajmera-b6144092/ | https://github.com/Sahil-Ajmera | +1(646)571-9799

CAREER SUMMARY

Dedicated engineer with a master's degree in Computer Science from Rochester Institute of Technology and experience working in the cloud infrastructure industry with companies like Oracle and Lenovo. Currently working at Oracle as a Member of Technical Staff in the Network Automation team. Always on the lookout for exciting new opportunities to grow.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York Master of Science in Computer Science Earned December 2019 GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal, Karnataka, India Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Earned 2017

SKILLS

Certifications: Oracle Certified Professional JAVA SE6 Programmer, Microsoft Technical Associate for Cloud

Fundamentals, Advanced Graduate Certificate: Big Data Analytics (ACT)

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C#

Database: MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle 11g, H2 Database Engine, Cassandra

Data Analysis Tools: SQL, R, Weka, Tableau, Minitab

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, Materialize

Desktop Application Development: Qt

Orchestration Tools: Juju Charms, Ansible Playbooks, Docker

Source Control: Git

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Member of Technical Staff Seattle, Washington February 2020 – Present

Lenovo

Morrisville, North Carolina August 2018 – May 2019

Software Development Co-op – Data Center Group

- Added features to Lenovo's RHHI offering by leading efforts on instantiation, configuration and validation of platforms like CloudForms, ManageIQ and Gitlab. (Presented at MWC-2019 and RH Summit 2019)
- Created a desktop application for ForkLift operators that gives information about the load they are carrying and the lane they are carrying that load to. (Presented at MWC-2019 and Lenovo Accelerate 2019)
- Created 3 Rapid Access Demos (RADs) as a means of proof of technology allowing customers and partners with remote testing of Lenovo Data Center solutions.
- Technologies used Python, C#, Juju Charms, Qt, MQTT, RHVM, CloudForms, ManageIQ, Ansible, Materialize, .NET

American Institutes For Research

Washington, District of Columbia

Software Engineer Intern

May 2018 – August 2018

- Integrated existing workflow of Item Card report generation into workflow of Custom Pdf report generation so that statistics of items can also be printed while making a Custom Pdf Report.
- Diagnosed bugs and implemented new features as per client requirements.
- Decreased the time that will take in later development operations by documenting existing code.
- Technologies Used: C#, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, SQL, SQL Server